MALEK FERHI

PROFILE

Software engineer from Tunisia, with 3 years of experience on .Net development and data engineering, Thomas Jefferson Scholar and alumni of Valencia College. Currently looking for a new challenge, in which I could demonstrate all the skills and expertise I have.

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

.NET FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT

Achats-marches.fr (Link to project)

OfficeDesMarches.fr (Link to project)

Contactini.tn (Link to project on GitHub)

Trip Advertisement Application (Link to project on GitHub)

.NET MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

WIN 8.1 store Application: "Drab ALHIDAYA" (Link to project)

Win Phone 8 Mobile App: "Happy New You" (Link to project on GitHub)

TUTORING STUDENTS

Providing courses and private help on .Net field (ASP MVC, C#, ASP.Net Core)

Datawarehousing and data Visualization

Web development, applications deployments and troubleshooting

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITIES

Member of the Microsoft Club of the university.

JCertif Student ambassador.

Firefox student ambassador.

SKILLS .NET ECOSYSTEM

- C#, ASP.Net MVC, .Net Standard, .Net Core, XAML, Web API development, Entity Framework, Identity Framework.
- Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SQL server, IIS, windows server 2016.
- Azure Active Directory, Azure Api Management, Azure App Services, Azure DevOps.
- Application deployment to Azure and to windows Server, Maintenance and debugging of applications.

PRINCIPLES, ARCHITECTURE, DESIGN

- Design Patterns: Abstract, Builder, Singleton, Bridge, Adapter, Mediator, Command, Memento, Observer, CQRS.
- Architectures: Serverless, Microservices, SOA, N-Tier, Monolithic.
- Principles: SDLC, OOAD, SOLID, KISS.

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Angular 7

DATAWAREHOUSING AND DATA VISUALIZATION

- Tableau Software, QlikView, QlikSense.
- Talend ETL, Talend Big Data
- Data integration, cleansing, Dimensional Modeling and analysis.
- Story Telling using data, Dashboards design and preparation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

.Net /BI developer Freelancer: Localhost Sousse (01/2018 - 12/2019)

As a freelancer, I worked on different types of projects/Tasks, that includes tutoring, Building Datawarehouse's, Data Visualization projects, web integration, applications' development, maintenance, troubleshooting and deployment, applications' migration from windows server 2008 to windows server 2016, databases' migration from SQL server 2008 to SQL server 2016. The technologies I used for these projects are:

- ASP.Net Core web api, ASP.Net MVC, Angular 7, C#, Visual Studio 2019, Visual Studio Code, SQL Server2008/2012/2016, Windows server 2016, GitLab, XUnit, Postman, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS, Microsoft AZURE, AZURE DevOps.
- Tableau Software, QlikView, QlikSense, Talend Data Integration, Talend Big Data, Excel.

Full Stack .Net developer: WMG-STUDIO TUNIS (06/2019 - Now)

Participation on the development of management application for the internal activities of startups such as employee's engagement and products profitability. The technologies used for the development are:

 ASP.Net Core web api, Angular 7, C#, Visual Studio 2019, Visual Studio Code, Nebular Theme, Entity Framework, Identity Framework, SQL Server, Windows server 2016, GitLab, XUnit, Postman, AuthO, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS.

Full Stack .Net developer intern: INTILAQ TUNIS (06/2019 – 10/2019)

Developing a Microservice as a part of course Material Exchange services application that helps students to acquire documents and courses' abstracts from their peers or from alumni's. The technologies used for the development are:

 ASP.Net core 2.2, C#, Angular, HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Entity Framework Core, Sql Server, Visual Studio 2019, Identity Framework, UML diagrams design, Microservices architecture, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Azure.

Full Stack .Net developer intern: DOTIT SOUSSE (06/2017 – 10/2017)

Development of a tourism application module that serves on helping users, especially tourists to find the closest Bars, coffee shops and restaurants along with several other options. The technologies used for the development are:

 ASP.Net MVC, C#, SendGrid, HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Entity Framework, Sql Server, Visual Studio 2015, Google Maps api, Leaflet JS, Identity Framework, UML diagrams design.

Page | 2 Malek Ferhi

Full Stack .Net developer intern: VALENCIA COLLEGE (01/2017 – 05/2017)

Developing a fully functional ASP MVC application for the Valencia Technology organization. Th application serves on managing the club activities. The technologies used for the development are:

 ASP.Net MVC, C#, SendGrid, HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Microsoft Azure, Entity Framework, Sql Server, Visual Studio 2015.

TRAINER & CLUB MEMBER: ISSATSO MICROSOFT CLUB (09/2014 - 09/2016)

My role includes participation on the events, competitions and conferences organized by the club for the university, besides, introducing students to the world of programming professional mobile applications.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING DEGREE

Higher Institute of Applied Sciences and Technology Sousse, expected graduation on June 2020

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, DATA SCIENCE TECHNICAL CERTIFICATES.

Valencia College, Orlando Florida USA, graduated May 2017

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native Language

English: Advanced
French: Advanced
Spanish: Beginner

AWARDS

Thomas Jefferson Scholarship

A fully sponsored academic and cultural exchange year in the United States, exactly at the Valencia College, Orlando

CITI Competition 2018: ARSII Sousse

Third Prize for the application "Awaken".

Startupper challenge

Third prize for the application "Smart Mirror".

Page | 3 Malek Ferhi